Today we're going to start a series
called Viral Recipes for the Ninja
Creamy. We're going to look at what they
are and just make them good.
This is the first in a probably a long
series where I'm going to look at viral
ice cream recipes that have been made in
the Ninja Creamy, try and explain why
they've done what they have, and make
that actual product somewhat edible. So,
first one is peaches. This recipe I you
can't even call it a recipe. This idea,
I literally didn't even want to go down
the rabbit hole as to where it came
from, but someone decided that they were
just going to call this ice cream by can
of peaches and put it in a blender or
freeze it in their Ninja Creamy tub and
then process it in there. So, I I get
that the Ninja Creamy it can be used
for, you know, healthy kind of snacks.
And if you're doing that, then don't
call it ice cream because that is just
frozen peaches and water or syrup,
depending on which one you buy.
Healthy snack. Yes, absolutely. Nothing
wrong with that. Don't start calling it
ice cream or gelato or sorbet cuz it's
not even anywhere close. can't even it's
not even in the same country let alone
ballpark. So I went to the store and
picked up these two different cans. Del
Monte and this is I think Western family
peaches which comes from Savon Foods
over here. Uh two very distinctly
different cans. the same peaches in
there which are clinging stone peaches
but per
167 milll so 2/3 of a cup uh this one
has 8 g of sugar this one has 22 g of
sugar they both have approximately the
same amount of protein uh same amount of
sodium give or take so pretty much the
same puff and sugar this one is
sweetened with sucralose so it contains
14 millig grams of sucralose to give you
a slightly more appropriate kind of
taste. Um, as if peaches aren't sweet
enough as they are, that that's that's
that. So, this is Clingstone Peaches,
water, citric acid, ascorbic acid, and
sucralose. Contains 14 milligs per
serving. This one is Clingstone Peaches,
water, sugar, citric acid. So, it's
actually a much cleaner label, but this
one, this uses white sugar, table sugar,
and this one uses sucralose. I'm not
going to compare the two because if
you're gonna just put this in an inch
cream and blend it, then what's the
point of even coming up with that idea?
But we can do something with this to
make it somewhat edible. What do we need
to make this semidecent? Not a lot
actually. We need a little bit of cream.
We're going to use some alulose. You can
use xylitol as well, but you'll just
need to use a bit less. And we're going
to build up the solids just enough with
a little bit of inulin and then a
stabilizer to grab hold of that excess
water. Pretty simple recipe. Let's get
what we need laid out here. So, we do
need to blend the peaches. So, that is
obviously a given. We've got our
whipping creams 33%. You can use 36% and
actually that would be a benefit. You
could use double cream as well, which
would also be a benefit because you're
actually just increasing solids, which
is where this this idea falls flat on
its ass. A lot of handwaving going on
today. So, we're going to open our
peaches. I'm using the Del Monte ones,
which are the sucralose sweetened ones.
We're going to open a can and pour that
whole thing
into our blender, syrup, and everything.
Now into here we need to add 100 g of
our cream. There we go. And then
additionally we're going to add in 70 g
of our alulos. Remember we're making ice
cream. We're not just freezing peaches
and saying it's ice cream. We're
actually making ice cream here. Uh we
need our inulin which I haven't got out.
Inulin is chory root fiber. That is all
it is. Um, it can make you a bit gassy
if you eat too much. It's a very small
amount going in here. And finally, it's
a stabilizer. There's loads of water in
here. Not enough solids. We need to
stabilize that free water. So, what
we're going to do is use zantham gum.
Why zantham gum? Well, gua gum is not
very good in acidic environments. Peach
are a mildly acidic fruit. So, we need
to make sure that we're using the right
stabilizer for the right job. If you use
a blend, that is absolutely fine because
the other parts of it will stabilize
your mix. If you're just using a single
stabilizer like go and to be fair, I
quite like guar um then think about when
you're using it. Tara gum also works in
here. And we are going to just add 1 g
of our zantham gum into there. That is
everything. Put this back in the fridge.
That is it. everything we need to turn
this useless recipe into something
actually closer to or achen to ice
cream. So, that in our blender, let's
get it in here. I'm going to blend it up
for a good minute or two. Get everything
mixed together. Get those peaches
decimated into a nice kind of liquid.
Right, there we go. Now, do we need to
heat this up? We've used a cold
processed stabilizer, zantham gum. So
the stabilizer doesn't need heating, but
the alulose often doesn't
dissolve properly without some kind of
heat. So what we can do is just check.
Run a spoon along the edge of your
container. There's absolutely no
graininess in there or whatsoever. Super
smooth. That alo has dissolved within
our liquid. So we're good to go. In this
goes, see, look, the texture is so so
much better. This gives you I think
about 600 g worth of base here. Into the
freezer that goes to completely harden
off. That's going to take, you know, I
I'd give it a day just to be sure. And
then we'll look at the the Ninja Creamy
hump. We'll look at the top here and
we'll see what the result is. So, I'll
come back once this is frozen. Inulin
comes from Amazon. There's loads of
different types. Just buy the cheapest
one cuz it's all the same. Chory root
fiber it's also known as. So if you
can't find inulin, look for a chory root
fiber. There are other types of fiber
sources as well. Citrus fiber is a
modern ingredient that's coming around.
I haven't been able to buy it yet, but I
know someone in Europe that can buy it.
Uh also someone in Mexico that can buy
it. So, it's coming and I reckon once
that turns up and becomes available to
the public, it will be a bit of a game
changer for these healthier recipes cuz
it's the it will be the perfect solids
boost for us. So, make sure to like and
subscribe if you want to see how to
change your bad ice cream recipe into a
good ice cream recipe. Let's get our
frozen peach ice cream base out of the
freezer. Right, the can of peaches just
frozen and ours. Let's have a look. I'm
not expecting this to be completely flat
because it's not a perfect recipe, but
it is much more appropriately flat.
There's a tiny little bump in the
middle, but it's pretty good. And that's
because we've got that solids content
just within the range that we want it to
be. This is technically the fat content
of gelato. Um, but it doesn't have the
sugar obviously because we we've gone
with no added sugar. We've used alulose,
but we we have changed the freezing
point and the serving temperature to be
in line with gelato as well. So, let's
chat. We plugged in. Yes. Let's fire
this up. We do the whole So, we're just
going to do ice cream. You can do gelato
if you want to. Look, I've never done
the gelato. If you don't know, the ice
cream and the gelato settings do exactly
the same thing. Speed, it rotation is
the same, drop speed, raise speed,
identical, it's the same thing. So, with
that set, let's do this.
Because the solids are still quite low,
we're going to give that one more go
just to make that really nice. And
[Music]
right, two spins required for that. Two
spins because the solids are still too
low really for good
ice cream. Quickly get the other one in.
No idea what to can of peaches only.
just the can of peaches and the adjusted
one here. Let's get some dished up and
then compare the results.
So there we go. All dished up,
ready to go. Now something to note is
this
can only result. It's kind of got the
texture to sorbet as you would expect,
but with ginormous ice crystals and they
are so big that you can see them on the
camera. I mean that means that they are
huge and that is literally because it's
it doesn't have the solids required, not
necessarily sugar because we know we can
do sugar-free doesn't have the solids
required to reduce the size of ice
crystals. There's nothing else to bind
to that water to make it actually
functional as a sorbet either. So,
you're just eating frozen mango, which
in itself is fine. If that's what you
want, then fine. The last part of this
video, I'll take those out and be very
short and you can actually see tomorrow.
Uh it is nearly half past 1 in the
afternoon. Tomorrow, you'll see the
result of the two and how one will scoop
much better than the other one. So
the can the can only is actually just
flopping around. It's melting so fast
that it's not pleasant. If it's the
summertime, this kind of thing would
absolutely work. I can see the appeal
for that. But do not call it ice cream.
With a few simple ingredients, it spoons
just like an ice cream. Much more
appropriate size ice crystals. So it's
smooth. It's got a lovely texture. It's
not melting anywhere near as fast. Let
me show you how quickly the the other
one is melting. I mean, look, it's
literally just been here for a few
minutes talking. And you can see the
difference. You can see just by using a
a can of fruit can produce something
frozen and cold, much like a smoothie,
cuz really that's kind of what it is in
bowl shaped. Uh I'll cut back to
tomorrow when we'll just show you the
the scoop. So, to close this video out,
I said I wanted to show you the
scoopability issues that a lot of these
ninja creamy recipes have. So, if you're
not going to eat an entire container,
then you need to put it back in the
freezer. Can of peaches only. And this
is the result.
It is impossibly hard. And this is my
fixed version of this.
Straight out. Good to go. No textural
change. The importance of understanding
how ice creams, gelatas, and sorbets
work means you don't have to fuff around
re-pinning time and time again. Anyway,
thanks very much for watching. Don't
forget to like and subscribe, and I will
see you next week.
[Music]